(木ノ葉丸)よくも俺たちの里を➡
How dare they turn our village
into a mess!
めちゃくちゃにしてくれたな
これ。
(ウドン)木ノ葉丸君！
Konohamaru-kun!
(モエギ)木ノ葉丸ちゃん！
Konohamaru-chan!
ウドン！ モエギ！
Udon! Moegi!
いいところに来たんだな。
Just in time.
里のピンチを 俺たちで救うぞ これ。
We're gonna save this village
from this disaster!
(ウドン)ええ!? せっかく僕たち➡
What? But we just managed
to run away.
あれから逃げてきたっていうのに。
ナルトの兄ちゃんが いない今➡
Naruto nii-chan is away.
里を守るのは俺たちの役目なんだ。
So it's our duty to protect the village!
そんなこと言ったって➡
Yeah, but there's nothing we can do
against such powerful monsters!
あんな強そうな化け物が相手じゃ。
あんなヤツ…
ナルト兄ちゃんから教わった新術で➡
I'll just blast 'em with the new jutsu
that Naruto nii-chan taught me!
一発だ！
新術？
New jutsu?!
(モエギ)どうせ
いつものエロ忍術でしょ？
It's probably the usual
Pervy Ninjutsu, right?
違う！
No, it's not!
((ナルト : 木ノ葉丸。
Konohamaru!
お前に教えたい術が
あるんだってばよ。
There's a jutsu I want to teach you!
急にどうしたんだ これ？
What's with you all of a sudden?
いやあ 俺もその なんちゅうか…。
Well, I... Um... How can I put it?
託される側から
託す側になるっていうか。
It's time I pass things on to others,
instead of being passed down to.
は？ 何言ってるんだ これ？
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
《まさか とんでもないエロ忍術を
思いついたのか これ？》
Don't tell me he came up with
some awesome Pervy Ninjutsu?!
ともかくだ！
これから お前に教える術は➡
A-Anyway! The jutsu I'm gonna teach
you is on a whole new level!
そんじょそこらの術とは
レベルが違うんだってばよ。
いいから 早く教えてくれよ。
Just hurry up and teach it to me!
《どんな
すごいエロ忍術なんだろう？》
I wonder what kind of
amazing Pervy Ninjutsu it is.
いいか？ まずは回転だ。
Listen up. First step is "rotation"!
おお！ 動きを加えるのか これ？
Whoa! We're going to add motion, eh?!
そして その次が威力。
And next is "power"!
きわどい系で攻める
ってことか？ これ！
Attack with the risqué, eh?!
そしてそして 更にその次が！
And then finally, there is...
ほぎょおお！
まだ この次があるのか？ これ！
There's even more?!
留める！
Containment!
The most points go to
the best expression, eh?!
いちばんのエロポイントで
決めポーズだ これ！
(何を言っているんだ？ お前…))
What are you talking about?
確かに俺も
最初はエロ忍術かと思った。
At first, I also thought
this was a Pervy Ninjutsu...
けど 違うんだ これ！
But it's different!
この術があれば
高いランクの任務だってこなせる。
With this jutsu, I can go
on high-ranking missions!
高いランクの任務って何よ？
What kind of high-ranking missions?!
私たちのやるべきことが
ちゃんとあるでしょ！
At a time like this,
we have things that we must do.
そうだよ 木ノ葉丸君！
僕たちには➡
She's right, Konohamaru-kun.
It's our duty to guide and
evacuate the civilians!
非戦闘員を避難誘導する
っていう➡
大事な任務があるじゃないか。
子供や戦えない人たちを
避難させるのか？ これ。
We're supposed to evacuate the children
and those who cannot fight, huh?
うん。 私はＣ地区の様子を➡
Yes! I'm going to check out
how things are in Block C.
見てくるわ。
僕はＥ地区を。
Right! I'll check on Block E.
なら 俺はＢ地区だ これ。
Then I'm going to Block B!
逃げ遅れた人がいないか
行ってみるんだな これ。
I'll make sure there's no one
who didn't make it out!
気をつけてね 木ノ葉丸ちゃん。
Be careful now, Konohamaru!
Anyone?! Is anyone here?!
誰か！ 誰かいないか これ！
誰か！
Anyone!
助けて…。
Help me!
Where? Where are you?!
どこだ？ これ！
どこにいるんだ？
うう…。
大丈夫か？
Are you all right?!
しっかりするんだこれ。
Hang on!
よくも こんなひどいことを！
How could they do this?!
融合が無理なら 動きながらでも➡
If we can't merge,
I have no choice
自然エネルギーを
取り込むしかねえじゃねぇか！
but to pull in Nature Energy
while I'm moving!
(フカサク)じゃけん
それは 無理なんじゃ。
And I said that's impossible!
まさか ここへきて
こんなことになるとは わしも…。
I never imagined this would
happen after coming this far.
俺は諦めねえぞ！
I'm not giving up!
それしかねえんなら
それをやるまでだ！
If that's what it takes,
then I'll keep at it until it works!
だから 無理じゃと
言うとろうがな。
But I'm saying it's impossible!
(フカサク)す すまん…。
I-I'm sorry...
とにかく 辛いじゃろうが
それは 物理的に無理なんじゃ。
I know this is hard to accept,
but it's physically impossible.
その背中の暗号は
エロ仙人から俺へのメッセージだ。
That code on your back was a message
to me from the Pervy Sage.
ああ わかっとる。
Yes, I know that.
じゃけん ナルトちゃんのおかげで
ペインの謎を解くカギに…。
And thanks to you, Naruto-chan,
it's become a key to solving
the mystery of Pain--
違げ～よ。
Not just that.
最後まで
あきらめんじゃねえって➡
It's also a message for me not to
give up until the very end.
そう俺に託した
メッセージでもあるんだよ。
だからといって…。
But still...
俺は エロ仙人の弟子だ。
I'm Pervy Sage's student.
そのメッセージが師匠の忍道なら
俺が…。
And if that message was
my master's Ninja Way... then I...
俺が弱音吐くわけには
いかねえんだよ！
I have no business whining!
what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Surname is Sarutobi! Given Name, Konohamaru!
Thank you...
ありがとう。
You'll be all right now.
もう大丈夫だぞ これ。
うわぁ！
うわ～！
うう！
That mark...
《あの模様は…。
It's the gang that killed
Uncle Asuma... The Akatsuki!
アスマおじちゃんを殺した一味 暁》
Is Uzumaki Naruto here in
the village or not? Which is it?
(地獄道)うずまきナルトは
この里にいるのか？
いないのか どっちだ？
Naruto?!
ナルトだって!?
アイツは 木ノ葉の仲間だ。
He's... a member of the village.
We would never sell out a comrade!
仲間を売るようなマネはしない
うっ！
火の意志とやらか。
The Will of Fire, eh?
ううっ！
なんだ？
What?!
俺の質問に答えなければ
次はない。
If you do not answer my question,
it is over for you.
もう一度聞く。
I will ask you one more time.
何だ これは…。
What is this?
Is Uzumaki Naruto here in
the village or not? Which is it?
うずまきナルトは この里にいるのか
いないのか どっちだ？
I know nothing!
俺は何も知らない。
さっさと失せろ！
So get lost!
We don't know a thing! Let us go!
知らないって言ってんだろ！
離せ！
そうか なら判決を下してやる。
I see...
Then I shall pass judgment.
お前のほうは
本当に知らなかったようだな。
It seems you truly did not know.
え？
Wh-What's going on?!
《な… 何だよ これ。
何もしてないのに➡
He didn't do a thing and
yet the guy on the left stopped moving?!
左側のおじちゃんが
動かなくなった。
What did he do?!
何したんだ アイツ。
中忍のおじちゃんが➡
Was the chunin fellow killed without
何の反撃もできずに
やられたのか これ。
being able to defend himself at all?
I-I'd better get away from here.
It's too dangerous!
とにかく ここから逃げなきゃ。
やばい！》
うっ！
Oh no! Is he on to me?!
《やべぇ 見つかっちゃったのか
これ!?》
(エビス)好き勝手やってくれた
ようですね。
It seems you went ahead
to do as you please!
I have no mercy for scum like you!
あなたのような外道は
私が決して許しませんぞ！
《エビス先生！》
Ebisu-sensei!
《今のうちに逃げるのです
木ノ葉丸君！》
Now is your chance to
get away, Konohamaru-kun!
どこを見ているのです！
Where do you think you're looking?!
この程度で私は
やられはしませんぞ！
It'll take more than that to kill me!
エ エビス先生…。
Ebisu-sensei...
《なんとしても 木ノ葉丸君の
逃げる時間を稼がなくては！》
I must buy some time to
allow Konohamaru to escape!
《どうしよう… どうしよう これ。
Wh-What'll I do? What'll I do?!
どうしたら…》
How can I...?
《よし 逃げたようですね》
Good... He got away.
ぬかりましたね。
I messed up...
だが 私の役目 果たせたようです。
But I've done what I needed to do.
うずまきナルトは この里に
いるのか いないのか？
Is Uzumaki Naruto here
in the village, or not?
知っているなら
どちらか はっきり答えろ。
If you know, speak up.
ナルト君…。
N-Naruto-kun?
《ナルトの兄ちゃん》
Naruto nii-chan?!
うずまきナルトは
知っているようだな。
It seems you do know Uzumaki Naruto.
なら 居場所を言え。
Then tell me where he is.
クッ 私は…。
I may... not look it...
こう見えても
エリート教師でしてね。
but I do hold the elite rank
of instructor.
ナルト君は 私の教え子。
Naruto-kun is my student.
昔 私は 彼のことを➡
Long ago, I considered him
a nuisance.
木ノ葉丸君の
火影への道を遠ざける ジャマ者➡
who stood in the way
of Konohamaru's rise to Hokage.
そう思っていました。
That's what I believed...
ですが ナルト君は
呪われた宿命にもめげず➡
However, Naruto-kun didn't allow
his cursed fate to discourage him.
持ち前の明るさと 負けん気で
数々の困難を乗り越えてきた。
With unending optimism and
a never-say-die attitude
he faced one challenge after
another and overcame them.
師である私が 教えられなかった
大切なことを➡
The important lessons
which I could not teach,
despite being an instructor,
彼は 私の生徒に教えてくれた。
he taught them to my students.
キサマ くだらぬ話を長々と。
You... have rambled on too long.
最後のチャンスだ。
This is your last chance.
ナルトの居場所を 知っているのか？
知らないのか？
Do you know where Naruto is,
or don't you?
はっきり答えろ。
でなければ殺す。
Answer me! Or else I'll kill you.
《ナルト君
キミは師匠の死を乗り越え➡
Naruto-kun... You...
You will overcome the death
of your master
その遺志を受け継ぎ進んでいく。
and carry on his legacy.
キミのその強い意志は 多くのことを
木ノ葉丸君に…。
The strong will you possess
will teach Konohamaru...
いや 里のみんなにも
教えてくれるはずです》
no, everyone in the village,
many things.
ナルト君は 木ノ葉の仲間です。
Naruto is a member
of the Hidden Leaf!
あなたたち 暁に
何も教えるつもりはありません。
I have no intention of telling
you Akatsuki anything!
《エビス先生》
Ebisu-sensei!
そうか ならば。
I see... Then...
《ナルト兄ちゃん》
Naruto nii-chan...
((みんな 俺を見るときや
俺を呼ぶとき➡
When people look at me
or call out to me,
ただ 火影の孫として見やがんだ！
they only see me as the grandson
of the Hokage.
もうイヤなんだ そんなの。
And I'm sick of it!
だから 今すぐにでも
火影の名前が欲しいんだ。
That's why I want the title
of Hokage right now!
簡単じゃねえんだ バーカ。
It's not easy, stupid!
火影 火影って そんなに
火影の名前がほしけりゃな。
You keep harping on about the Hokage.
If you want that title so badly...
この俺を
ぶっ倒してからにしろ。
you can have it over
my dead body!
これからは ライバルだ。
Then starting now... we're rivals!
いつか 火影の名をかけて➡
One day, we'll fight over
the name of Hokage.
お前とは 勝負してやんよ。
それまで 楽しみにしとけよな。
So look forward to that day,
Konohamaru!
(木ノ葉丸))
《どうやら
ここまでのようですね。
I guess this is the end of the road.
木ノ葉丸君は
うまく逃げられたでしょうか》
I hope that Konohamaru-kun was
able to escape.
死ね。
Die...
俺が相手だ これ！
I'll take you on!
俺は教わったんだ
忍の道に近道なんてないことを。
I was taught that...
there's no shortcut in the world
of the ninja!
木ノ葉丸君
どうして逃げなかったのです。
Konohamaru!
Why didn't you run away?!
あなたは いずれ
火影にもなられる器を持っている。
You have the potential to one day
become a Hokage!
こんなところで
命を粗末にしてはなりません。
Do not waste your life in
a place like this!
昔 約束したんだ これ。
I made a promise long ago.
ナルトの兄ちゃんと
火影の名をかけて➡
To fight Naruto nii-chan over
the title of Hokage...
いつか勝負するって
約束したんだ。
That's what we promised.
兄ちゃんは 俺のライバルだ これ。
Naruto nii-chan is my rival!
だから 俺は
逃げ道なんか選ばねえ。
So I'll never choose to run away!
そんな道の先に
ナルト兄ちゃんはいねえから！
Because Naruto nii-chan won't be waiting
at the end of that short path!
速い！
So fast!
うわっ！
うぅ…。
あっ！ あぁ…。
《とにかく コイツに捕まったら
ダメなことは確かだ これ。
One thing's certain.
If he catches me, I'm dead.
捕まると 何かしらの特殊な術で
殺されちゃう》
If I'm caught, he'll kill me with
some special jutsu.
うわっ！
木ノ葉丸君！
Konohamaru-kun!
うわっ！
先生！
S-Sensei!
うずまきナルトは この里に
いるのか いないのか どちらだ。
Is Uzumaki Naruto here in
the village or not? Which is it?
《そうか 捕まると
コイツが見えるのか》
I get it... So this is what you see
if you get caught.
さあ 答えろ。
Now, answer me.
((お前のほうは
本当に知らなかったようだな))
It seems you truly did not know.
《コイツの能力
だんだんわかったきたぞ》
I'm starting to figure out... his ability.
そんなの知らねえよ これ。
I don't have a clue!
木ノ葉丸君。
Konohamaru-kun?!
ナルトの兄ちゃん…。
N-Naruto nii-chan...
((木ノ葉丸 お前に
教えたい術があるんだってばよ。
Konohamaru! There's a jutsu
I want to teach you!
(術の会得難易度Ａランク))
It's an A-Rank level jutsu in terms
of difficulty to master.
うっ うぅ…。
そうか なら判決…。
I see. Then I shall pass judgment...
影分身！
A Shadow Clone?!
((チャクラの回転 威力 留めるを
極めた 超高等忍術))
Super advanced ninjutsu that combines
chakra rotation, power,
and containment...
螺旋丸！
- Rasengan!
《いつのまに こんな…》
Wh-When did he learn... such a...?
里の名を授かった
猿飛一族の下忍！
I am a genin of the Sarutobi clan,
honored with the name
of this village!
姓は猿飛 名は木ノ葉丸！
Surname is Sarutobi!
Given name is Konohamaru!
覚えとけ これっ！
Remember that!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
イテッ！
Oww!
まだまだ！ 次 いくってばよ！
Not just yet!
Let's keep on going!
この修業は 誰もが
できるというわけではない。
This training is not for everyone...
ナルトちゃんと
自来也ちゃんだからこそのもの。
You could say it's only possible
because it's you and Jiraiya-boy.
そう言ってもええ。
Or else I wouldn't have even
brought you here.
じゃなきゃ ここへは連れてこん。
己の内に 膨大なチャクラを持つ者。
Unless you already possess
enormous chakra inside you,
でなけりゃ たちまち 自然エネルギーに
取り込まれてしまうけんのう。
Nature Energy would just
take over you right away.
そのうえ 諦めん
ど根性のある者。
Plus, they must have the guts
to never give up.
それが 仙人になれる人間じゃ。
That's the kind of person
who can become a Sage.
フッ！
ったく 頑固なヤツじゃのう。
He's so stubborn...
少しは 休みんさい ナルトちゃん。
Let's take a break, Naruto-chan.
これじゃ わしが持たんがな。
Otherwise, I won't be able
to keep up.
ダメだってばよ！
That's no good!
We have to keep going to make up
今までの修業にかかった時間を
チャラにするぐれぇ➡
for the time we spent on
the training up until now!
ガンガンやんねえと！
大体な こんな修業は 今まで
したことありゃせんしのう…。
Look, you've never had this kind
of training before.
「動くな」が基本の 自然エネルギーを
走りながら集めるとは➡
To run and gather Nature Energy,
for which the foundation
is being still,
これじゃ 右を見とるときに➡
is like telling you to look to the left,
when you are looking to the right.
左も見ろと
言うとるようなもんじゃ！
あぁ～!!
なんじゃ？
What is it?
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
Next Episode
(香憐)
今度こそ ウチの色香で サスケを…。
You all push death out of your thoughts.
ヒヒヒ…。
In battle, both sides suffer death, injury, and pain.
これで オッケー。
Feel pain. Contemplate pain.
(サスケ)何が オッケーなんだ？
サスケが どうしてもって言うなら
背中 流してやるよ。
Accept pain. Know pain.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Pain to the World"
Pain to the World
断る！
あん！ もう！
そんな ツレないこと言うなよ～。
Almighty Push!
(水月)ふぅ～！ 極楽…。
(香憐)キャッ！
Inn Okoshi
水月 テメエ 何してやがんだ！
Men's Bath
"Women's Bath"
キミこそ 何してんだ？
え？
This time, for sure,
I'll use my sex appeal to get Sasuke.
ウチは… だから… その…。
テメエには関係ねえ！
チッ！ せっかくのチャンスだったのに！
でも まあ…。
This should be okay!
こいつが手に入ったから いっか。
ヒヒヒ！
What's okay?
サスケ… 僕のハブラシ知らない？
If you insist, Sasuke...
I'll wash your back.
No thanks.
Aww, c'mon, don't be so boring.
検束部隊から 緊急連絡！
新生オラシオンセイスの狙いは
教会の破壊にあらず！
This is sheer heaven...
狙いは かくまわれている
星霊魔導士とのこと！
What the hell are you doing, Suigetsu?!
至急 捜索し 保護せよ！
I'd ask the same of you!
Huh?! I just happen to...
(ナツ)急に
慌ただしくなってきやがった…。
I mean... well...
None of your business!
Damn it...
It was the perfect opportunity.
Oh well... At least I got this...
Sasuke, have you seen
my toothbrush?